<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>i'm lesley - A blog about things that interest me</title>
    <description>I'm lesley, I am an e-commerce developer, open source maintainer, and I have a life outside of my work. This blog is about those things that interest me</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:09:39 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:09:39 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Illegals and Drivers Licenses</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This has been a hot button topic for the last several years. I saw it was revived again last week when Minnesota allowed illegal immigrants to apply for drivers licenses. Every legislative cycle this debate comes up in at least one state and I would like to weigh in with my take on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-was-in-an-accident&quot;&gt;I was in an accident&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know me personally, you know a couple years ago an illegal immigrant hit me and my wife as we were returning hme from dinner. I broke my sternum and bruised my internal organs from the abrupt collision, she on the other had ruptured several disks in her neck and broke her shoulder blade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a somewhat traumatic experience and at the time and we did not really get a chance to confer with driver of the other vehicle. We actually were in a ride share car at the time and after EMS checked us out, we decided to hail another car and go home. That was a mistake looking back, since 3 hours later we were both in the emergency room, but I digress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having this experience did teach me a lot though, I learned more about the problem, ways to solve the problem, and the short comings with our system currently. So I feel like with my first hand knowledge I might have a better understanding of the issue than some people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-live-in-tennessee&quot;&gt;I live in Tennessee&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or maybe Nashville to be more specific. Nashville used to actually allow illegal immigrants to get drivers licenses, but that was struck down in recent years. I am not sure how the laws work or are written in other states, but Nashville is very interesting (to me at least) in their driving laws. See in Tennessee there are two distinct crimes around driving. One is driving without a license, that can carry up to a $50 fine and 30 days in jail. The other is driving on a suspended license. That can carry a $2500 fine and 11 months 29 days in jail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a big difference in my mind. After our accident I did a bit of digging, the man that hit us had been arrested 5 times for driving without a license, but never incarcerated. This is actually pretty relevant thing, since in Tennessee driving without a license does not qualify for a habitual crime, but driving on a suspended license does. If the driver that hit us had been driving on a suspended license, he never actually would have hit us, he would have been in jail from 1-6 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-a-solution&quot;&gt;Whats a solution?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like licensing them would be a solution, while at the same time moving the unlicensed drivers into the same class as the people that drive on a suspended license. That way they would have no reason to not get a drivers license. This way, we can move the “undocumented” people out of the shadows in a sense. Right now in Tennessee, like most states, if you do not have a valid drivers license you cannot obtain car insurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man that hit me and my wife did not have car insurance, I have no clue if it was because of his own doing, or because how insurance companies work with licensing restrictions. Either way, I was hit by someone that could not obtain insurance even if he wanted to. To me that creates a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What compounds this even more in my mind is the history of the guy that hit us. Looking deeper into his history I found he was actually a licensed driver at one time. There was a time that Tennessee allowed illegal immigrants to get drivers licenses, during that time he got one. I have no clue if he followed through and had insurance, but at least he did choose the route to be documented somehow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-think&quot;&gt;What I think&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like we should issue a drivers license to anyone over a specific age that can pass the test. Of course there needs to be documentation requirements so we know who we are actually issuing a license too, but that is a simple part of the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you noticed in this post I have referred to people as illegal immigrants, because well grammatically that is what they are. Undocumented workers or undocumented immigrants seems to be the popular term these days. But if you actually think about it, they do not have a real option to be documented. Issuing licenses to this group of people allows them a soft way into the system and a frictionless way to start to be documented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also allows them to be insured drivers too. For the life of me I cannot understand the argument against allowing illegal immigrants, that are already driving, to have car insurance. Its not to protect their assets, it is to protect other drivers on the road. Sure, maybe some will get full coverage and they will get their cars repaired too, but really, is that bad? Most immigrants have come to America for a better life, they try to fly under the radar and not cause problems. Lets give them a chance to be documented while also taking responsibility for their driving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know Nashville, there really is not a public transportation argument for keeping these drivers off the road. We have a very lacking system here, even the ideas that have been proposed are lacking and shortsighted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/drivers-licenses/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/drivers-licenses/</guid>
        
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Internet Sales Tax</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you know me, you know I have worked in the e-commerce industry for around 10 years. If you are not familiar with me, I have worked in the e-commerce industry for around 10 years, nice to meet you. In the last few years, specifically last year, internet sales tax has been a hot topic. As a professional in the e-commerce industry, let me come out and say I am for an e-commerce sales tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why&quot;&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taxes suck, I think everyone can agree on that. But the situation we have gotten ourselves into sucks even worse. Last year a major court case was lost, it might have went under the radar of people not in the industry, but it was a stark awaking for people in the e-commerce industry. South Dakota vs Wayfair was decided by the Supreme Court of the United States in June of 2018. To paraphrase the ruling, it allows states to charge sales tax even when a company does not have a nexus in that state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-does-that-mean&quot;&gt;What does that mean?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you remember the old as seen on tv commercials, you likely remember the quick words at the end where they would say so-and-so state has to pay sales tax. Its because that is the state the business is in. What this ruling means is that no longer matters, any state can require any company that does sales in that state to pay sales tax. In the past the burden was on the consumer, which admittedly I can imagine none remitted sales tax. But this shift to e-commerce companies is quite burdensome and worrisome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-it-works-now&quot;&gt;How it works now&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine throwing tax code at the wall and hoping some sticks. That is what we have now after the Wayfair ruling. As of January 1st 2019 32 states collect sales tax if you sell in their states with no nexus. Seems simple, right? Actually… Merchants have to deal with 32 different idiosyncrasies.  See the table below on how tax is currently collect in the 33 participating states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;State&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Requirements&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Rhode Island&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$100,000 or 200 transactions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Hawaii&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$100,000 or 200 transactions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Washington&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$100,000 or 200 transactions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Idaho&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$10,000&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Maine&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$100,000 or 200 transactions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Oklahoma&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$10,000&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Vermont&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$100,000 or 200 transactions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Mississippi&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$250,000&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Alabama&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$250,000&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Illinois&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$100,000 or 200 transactions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Indiana&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$100,000 or 200 transactions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Kentucky&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$100,000 or 200 transactions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Maryland&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$100,000 or 200 transactions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Massachusetts&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$500,000 or 100 transactions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Michigan&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$100,000 or 200 transactions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Minnesota&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;10 retail transaction totaling $100,000 or 100 retail transaction&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;North Dakota&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$100,000 or 200 transactions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Wisconsin&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$100,000 or 200 transactions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;New Jersey&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$100,000 or 200 transactions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;North Carolina&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$100,000 or 200 transactions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;South Carolina&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$100,000&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;South Dakota&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$100,000 or 200 transactions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Colorado&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$100,000 or 200 transactions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Connecticut&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$100,000 or 200 transactions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Arkansas&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$100,000 or 200 transactions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Georgia&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$100,000 or 200 transactions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Iowa&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$100,000 or 200 transactions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Louisiana&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$100,000 or 200 transactions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Nebraska&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$100,000 or 200 transactions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Utah&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$100,000 or 200 transactions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;West Virgina&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$100,000 or 200 transactions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;New York&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$300,000 or 200 transactions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;California&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$100,000 or 200 transactions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;looks-simple-right&quot;&gt;Looks simple, right?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, its not, its actually quite complex and burdensome to small e-commerce shops. If you think about it on a purely numerical level, its the kind of change that can put companies out of business. I take a lot of my thoughts and opinions from what I see in the real world, so let me extrapolate. The majority of the states have a $100,000 or 200 transaction limit. But what does that really mean? 200 transactions is not a lot of transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider a company that sells t-shirts. T-shirts generally sell in the $15-$20 range, and the site make about $5-$8 off of each shirt sold. So lets just use Maine as an example. If you sell 210 t-shirts to Maine at $20 apiece, you would gross $4200. Of that you would actually profit, between $1600 and $1050. But now you have to deal with tax remittance. This is a huge added cost to merchants, especially small merchants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-costs&quot;&gt;The costs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The costs start to pile up pretty quickly when dealing with this taxation system. See, there are no e-commerce shopping carts that can handle tax in the US correctly. Not many people realize it, but there are over 10,000 different sales tax zones in the US. Most states have base sales tax, then the counties add a sales tax on top of that. Then the cities or towns in the counties can add a tax on that. Sales tax is complicated to collect for internet retailers. Sales tax cannot be figured by just zip codes, zip codes bleed over into multiple tax zones frequently. Tax has to be figured by the actual address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, since you have to figure tax by the address, you need an external service to do that. That is where companies like Avalara or Tax Cloud come in. You either pay a monthly fee, or a fee per tax lookup so that your site can figure and collect tax properly. That is another added expense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You then have to start applying for sales tax permits in these different states. That cost money. You have to have an accountant file taxes for you in multiple states, that cost even more money. If you don’t sell enough one year to be taxed in a state, you still have to file, or you will get penalized. That costs even more money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-oh-fuck-moment&quot;&gt;The oh fuck moment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happens when you have an “oh fuck” moment? Think about this, you sell t-shirts, last year you look at your sales and you sold 45 shirts to Maine, so you do not need to collect sales tax in Maine. You release a cool t-shirt this year, and for some strange reason people in Maine love it. You sell 400 shirts in Maine this year. But “oh fuck” you did not collect sales tax in Maine this year, because your last year sales were too low. You would have to pay the tax out of your pocket, or try to fly under the radar and hope not to get noticed (break the law).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These laws, with their high dollar limits look like they are targeted at large businesses, unfortunately they are not. They were actually lobbied for by bigger businesses to squash out their smaller rivals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-proposal&quot;&gt;My proposal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why I am for an e-commerce sales tax. A flat tax. All sales are taxed at that rate, then remitted to the nexus state. This would require either none or minimal extra accounting to the e-commerce sites, it would provide tax revenue to the states. It would not give one state an advantage over the others, it would be flat and fair. Something needs to be done with e-commerce tax legislation or we will end up with only a handful of large e-commerce sites, and small sites will be put out of business like small mom and pop stores were put out of business. These tax laws are an attack on small businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/internet-sales-tax/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/internet-sales-tax/</guid>
        
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
        <category>ecommerce</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Milk</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Milk, who doesn’t love milk? Well, besides the lactose intolerant, vegans, PETA, and a host of other people. Let’s forget about those people though for the context of this article. This post is more along the naming conventions of products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read an article today that the Arizona house today voted to OK labels calling Almond Milk fake milk. This seems like a stupid law, how could people not realize that almond milk was not actually milk? But to me it runs deeper than that. Its not just about almond milk, or even milk in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nut-juice&quot;&gt;Nut Juice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sounds crazy, right? But honestly that is what I think it should be called, or almond juice, or drink or whatever. Its not milk. I have heard the dumbing down of America arguments, people argue that anyone can look at a label and tell that the milk is not cows milk. I do not argue with that, as a drinker of almond milk, I would say you have to be pretty unobservant to mistake the two. I don’t see that as the real problem though, I see it as a deeper problem with deeper implications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;juice&quot;&gt;Juice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is juice? What is apple juice? Apple juice is juice squeezed from apples. Apple juice is also 60% water 30% white cane sugar, and 10% apple concentrate. Both are apple juice and marketed as apple juice. Which one is really apple juice though? This creates confusion in the market. Of course it is more costly to grind up a bunch of apples, filter out the skin, chunks, and impurities than it is to take concentrate and add water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;business&quot;&gt;Business&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sole purpose of businesses is to generate money. If you are a multi-national public corporation like most companies that produce almond milk, you also have a duty to provide value to your shareholders. What if you are represented in both markets though? Of the top 3 almond milk producers, two of them also have massive dairy holdings. One of them has venture capital money that comes from stake holders in other dairy companies. So its not out of line to say that dairy has a hand in almond milk wanting to be able to be labeled with milk. But this seems counter to their interests, since they have dairy holdings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cheaper-milk-products&quot;&gt;Cheaper Milk Products&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A long game is being played right before our eyes and most of us are not even aware. Right now milk has a FDA definition, its&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Description. Milk is the lacteal secretion, practically free from colostrum, obtained by the complete milking of one or more healthy cows. Milk that is in final package form for beverage use shall have been pasteurized or ultrapasteurized, and shall contain not less than 8 1/4 percent milk solids not fat and not less than 3 1/4 percent milkfat. Milk may have been adjusted by separating part of the milkfat therefrom, or by adding thereto cream, concentrated milk, dry whole milk, skim milk, concentrated skim milk, or nonfat dry milk. Milk may be homogenized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/scripts/cdrh/cfdocs/cfcfr/cfrsearch.cfm?fr=131.110&quot;&gt;read the whole description here&lt;/a&gt;, it is rather long and boring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point is milk is clearly defined currently. When companies with holdings in the dairy industry want to reduce the regulations on what can be called milk, I find it interesting. Why would companies want to dilute the current protections they have? Maybe they have another motive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-if&quot;&gt;What If&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if the reason is to dilute their milk products? I have no problem admitting I do not trust companies or their motives, so I find the situation suspect. The only thing I can figure is that the almond milk and dairy companies’ end game is dilute their milk products. The dollars do make sense in the long run, if the companies can sell milk that is not 100% cow milk, then they can make more money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To circle back around, this is what the juice companies have done. There was a time that all fruit juice contained only juice. That time has passed and now it can contain added sugar, extra water, and other ingredients. I think this is precisely where the milk industry is going and they are using their alternative “milk” holdings to push this agenda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dumbing down of America argument was designed by these companies and their interests. We should push back against them. I personally think there is something wrong when my lemonade contains no actual lemon products, but my household cleaner does.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/milk/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/milk/</guid>
        
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
        <category>companies</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Medicare for All</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Medicare for all is a hot topic these days. It might be one of the hottest topics in the election coming up next year. Almost all democratic candidates for president in the next election have embraced it, some have put out plans for it as well. Personally, I am for medicare for all, but on a fiscal level I think all of the candidates are wrong on how to implement it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-are-they-wrong&quot;&gt;Why are they wrong?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest argument that the republican party gives is that we cannot afford medicare for all. This is where I want to start. I do not think under any of the proposed plans that we can actually afford it. All of the plans end up ballooning our debt, this is something I am strictly against.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;here-is-my-proposal&quot;&gt;Here is my proposal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think we need to add a new tax. People hate new taxes, that makes my idea immediately unpopular. While I am being unpopular, I want to raise taxes as well. Hear me out before you click away. Bernie’s plan comes the closest to what I would propose, but I would take it a step further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sanders plan includes adding a new 11% tax to payroll to help fund the medicare for all. 7.5% to be paid by the employer and 4% to be paid by the employee. This is one key place I would raise taxes. I would introduce a sliding scale.  My idea would raise the payroll tax to 15%, but add a couple new caveats. The first of which, is that the employer can choose to pay the whole 15%, but can pay no less than 7.5%. The second caveat is that I would introduce a &lt;strong&gt;CITY by CITY&lt;/strong&gt; income scale, based on where the employer’s office is and where the employees work. In this scale, there will be a floor income range. In this income range, it will penalize the employer by assigning a different percentage of the health care tax they have to pay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an illustration, for the sake of round numbers I am going to work off the current federal minimum wage and the cost of living in Nashville. The minimum wage is where the floor needs to be set, since it is the minimum that an employee can be paid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7.25 * 40 * 52 = 15,080 per year&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I cannot find good reliable statistics, lets say the cost of living in Nashville is $2000 a month. An employee making the federal minimum wage is $4,820 below the floor in Nashville. So employees making minimum wage would realize no new tax on their checks, instead the employer would pay the full 15%. Once an employees pay hits the floor, for every percent they are above the floor, a half percent will be reduced from the employers contribution and shifted to the employee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea behind this is two fold. The first is that there are huge differences in the quality of living in different parts of the country. When a 1 bedroom apartment costs $2000 in NYC and costs $600 for the same level of apartment in another city, we cannot use the same scale. The second line of thought is you do not consume the whole employee raise with new taxes, it is a gradual shift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a side note, when you age out of the workforce, the new tax for medicare for all vanishes, but also, the standard medicare and social security taxes vanish as well. This will free up more money for seniors, without the government having to take more money in and spend an overcost to disburse it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am just a regular guy, I do not have a CBO behind me to calculate the numbers, the economic impact, I am just building off of what I have seen other candidates use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shoring-up-the-other-gap&quot;&gt;Shoring up the other gap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is another gap with medicare. It does not bring in enough money to actually fund itself. For both the new tax I am proposing and the existing medicare social security tax, the limit would need to be lifted. Right now, individuals that make over $128k a year do not pay any social security on the earnings over $128k. I propose to lift these ceilings. Sure, some people will not like it, namely the people that make over $128k. Taxes are supposed to be proportional, this is not proportional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am prepared to argue all day long that the $3750 that a person makes $50,000 a year is worth more to them than the $37,500 that a person that makes $500,000 a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a good starting place, I would love to see the numbers it generates, but unfortunately I am not in a position to actually be able to generate them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/medicare-for-all/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/medicare-for-all/</guid>
        
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Banknotes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Late last year I was browsing the internet late at night and came across a site selling banknotes. I started looking through them and I was fascinated. Looking at all of the different notes around the world was pretty interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of them were pretty low tech as far as how they were designed, while others are a lot more hi-tech than the US notes I am used to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-2-24/romania.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Romanian &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like this polymer Romanian note from 1999. It has a ton of security features, including a clear panel where you can see the wood grain of my desk. Seeing the American notes from the late 90’s, well even the ones today, I realized that our money is kind of behind the times. The US dollar has pretty much looked the same all of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kind of dig these ever changing notes from different countries, but that does add a bit of cost in collecting, when a country issues a new design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hard-to-get-notes&quot;&gt;Hard to get notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you noticed the note in the top of the post, that was one that was a little harder to get. Its a North Korean Won. The embargoes we have with DPRK make it difficult to currency from there. That compounded with I don’t think people actually leave there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-2-24/rial.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Iranian Rial&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or like the Rial above featuring Ayatollah Khomeini from Iran. Since the US does not trade with Iran, they are increasingly harder to get. Not like super rare, but no where near the conversion rate either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a funny story about getting them actually. I ordered the won, the rial, some syrian dollars, and a few other banknotes one night in a drunken shopping spree. The federal government placed a hold and an investigation on my order. I actually got an email about it. It took around 3 days, but my account and that specific transaction were frozen. It was more annoying than anything, but I guess it is something to watch out for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-2-24/libya.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Libyan Dinar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is just something fascinating about all of this to me. I remember Libya from &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Back to the Future&lt;/code&gt;, now I own Libyian Dinar with Gaddafi on them before the US deposed him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me it is like owning a bit of history. So far I have around 800 or so different notes, with plans on buying more. The conversion value of them is low, but to me the art value of them is high.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/banknotes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/banknotes/</guid>
        
        
        <category>hobbies</category>
        
        <category>banknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Starting Growing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are familiar with me, you know that I work from an office in my home. I have an awesome commute, but it gets boring looking at the same walls every day. So lately I have started picking up more hobbies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The newest hobby is trying my hand at growing things. I bought some succulents at first, which I have managed to keep alive for several months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-2-20/long-pot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Long succulent pot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far they seem to be doing well. I am not an expert, but at least they are not dead yet. Trying my hand at the succulents made me want to branch out even more. I decided to start a garden this year and try growing some of my own food and spices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I searched around online and bought a ton of seeds from several different vendors, so I could start the seeds indoors, to have plants to plant when the weather warmed up. For the most part this worked pretty well. Almost all of the seeds I planted germinated and started to grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-2-20/plants.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Long succulent pot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is only a small fraction of what germinated, I have a feeling I went a bit overboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far what I have sprouting is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Green Zebra Tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dark Galaxy Tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Black Krim Tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pink Brandywine Tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cherokee Purple Tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Atomic Grape Tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get Stuffed Tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for peppers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aji Charapita&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brazilian Starfish&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Carolina Reapers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Apocalypse Scorpions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paprika&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Manganji&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And spices&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cilantro&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lemon Cilantro&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oregano&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Large Leaf Basil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lime Basil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know, its a bit overboard, but I cannot wait to see how things make it in the garden, that I have still yet to build. I guess the beds for the garden will be another post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/growing-things/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/growing-things/</guid>
        
        
        <category>hobbies</category>
        
        <category>gardening</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Break In</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week when I was minding my own business working on a project, a guy had different designs for me. He decided that he wanted to break into the toolbox on my truck. I guess unlucky for him all I have in my toolbox is some bags of cat food and charcoal I bought at a going out of business sale for a grocery store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can only imagine how mad my feral cats would be if he had taken the cat food, luckily enough for them he left empty handed. I did get a video him doing though, which to me is a fun watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1vm3wqpvxb8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes the situation even more ironic, or worse, is that after he left my house, he drove a little way down the street and broke into my neighbors truck as well. Because of the angle of the other camera, I have that on tape as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DmiddU7qhww&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anyone is wondering, I have an Ezviz camera system, it is the 1080p model. I thought it was a good system, but in the dark (when crime usually happens) the detail is just not there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/break-in/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/break-in/</guid>
        
        
        <category>life things</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
