<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>i'm lesley - A blog about things that interest me</title>
    <description>Jekyll Template for Blogging</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 10:59:55 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 10:59:55 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Banknotes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Late last year I was browsing the internet late at night and came across a site selling banknotes. I started looking through them and I was fascinated. Looking at all of the different notes around the world was pretty interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of them were pretty low tech as far as how they were designed, while others are a lot more hi-tech than the US notes I am used to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-2-24/romania.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Romanian &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like this polymer Romanian note from 1999. It has a ton of security features, including a clear panel where you can see the wood grain of my desk. Seeing the American notes from the late 90’s, well even the ones today, I realized that our money is kind of behind the times. The US dollar has pretty much looked the same all of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kind of dig these ever changing notes from different countries, but that does add a bit of cost in collecting, when a country issues a new design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hard-to-get-notes&quot;&gt;Hard to get notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you noticed the note in the top of the post, that was one that was a little harder to get. Its a North Korean Won. The embargoes we have with DPRK make it difficult to currency from there. That compounded with I don’t think people actually leave there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-2-24/rial.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Iranian Rial&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or like the Rial above featuring Ayatollah Khomeini from Iran. Since the US does not trade with Iran, they are increasingly harder to get. Not like super rare, but no where near the conversion rate either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a funny story about getting them actually. I ordered the won, the rial, some syrian dollars, and a few other banknotes one night in a drunken shopping spree. The federal government placed a hold and an investigation on my order. I actually got an email about it. It took around 3 days, but my account and that specific transaction were frozen. It was more annoying than anything, but I guess it is something to watch out for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-2-24/libya.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Libyan Dinar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is just something fascinating about all of this to me. I remember Libya from &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Back to the Future&lt;/code&gt;, now I own Libyian Dinar with Gaddafi on them before the US deposed him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me it is like owning a bit of history. So far I have around 800 or so different notes, with plans on buying more. The conversion value of them is low, but to me the art value of them is high.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/banknotes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/banknotes/</guid>
        
        
        <category>hobbies</category>
        
        <category>banknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Starting Growing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are familiar with me, you know that I work from an office in my home. I have an awesome commute, but it gets boring looking at the same walls every day. So lately I have started picking up more hobbies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The newest hobby is trying my hand at growing things. I bought some succulents at first, which I have managed to keep alive for several months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-2-20/long-pot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Long succulent pot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far they seem to be doing well. I am not an expert, but at least they are not dead yet. Trying my hand at the succulents made me want to branch out even more. I decided to start a garden this year and try growing some of my own food and spices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I searched around online and bought a ton of seeds from several different vendors, so I could start the seeds indoors, to have plants to plant when the weather warmed up. For the most part this worked pretty well. Almost all of the seeds I planted germinated and started to grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-2-20/plants.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Long succulent pot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is only a small fraction of what germinated, I have a feeling I went a bit overboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far what I have sprouting is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Green Zebra Tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dark Galaxy Tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Black Krim Tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pink Brandywine Tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cherokee Purple Tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Atomic Grape Tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get Stuffed Tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for peppers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aji Charapita&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brazilian Starfish&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Carolina Reapers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Apocalypse Scorpions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paprika&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Manganji&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And spices&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cilantro&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lemon Cilantro&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oregano&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Large Leaf Basil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lime Basil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know, its a bit overboard, but I cannot wait to see how things make it in the garden, that I have still yet to build. I guess the beds for the garden will be another post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/growing-things/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/growing-things/</guid>
        
        
        <category>hobbies</category>
        
        <category>gardening</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Break In</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week when I was minding my own business working on a project, a guy had different designs for me. He decided that he wanted to break into the toolbox on my truck. I guess unlucky for him all I have in my toolbox is some bags of cat food and charcoal I bought at a going out of business sale for a grocery store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can only imagine how mad my feral cats would be if he had taken the cat food, luckily enough for them he left empty handed. I did get a video him doing though, which to me is a fun watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1vm3wqpvxb8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes the situation even more ironic, or worse, is that after he left my house, he drove a little way down the street and broke into my neighbors truck as well. Because of the angle of the other camera, I have that on tape as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DmiddU7qhww&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anyone is wondering, I have an Ezviz camera system, it is the 1080p model. I thought it was a good system, but in the dark (when crime usually happens) the detail is just not there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/break-in/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/break-in/</guid>
        
        
        <category>life things</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
