<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>i'm lesley - A blog about things that interest me</title>
    <description>Jekyll Template for Blogging</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:07:03 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:07:03 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Medicare for All</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Medicare for all is a hot topic these days. It might be one of the hottest topics in the election coming up next year. Almost all democratic candidates for president in the next election have embraced it, some have put out plans for it as well. Personally, I am for medicare for all, but on a fiscal level I think all of the candidates are wrong on how to implement it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-are-they-wrong&quot;&gt;Why are they wrong?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest argument that the republican party gives is that we cannot afford medicare for all. This is where I want to start. I do not think under any of the proposed plans that we can actually afford it. All of the plans end up ballooning our debt, this is something I am strictly against.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;here-is-my-proposal&quot;&gt;Here is my proposal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think we need to add a new tax. People hate new taxes, that makes my idea immediately unpopular. While I am being unpopular, I want to raise taxes as well. Hear me out before you click away. Bernie’s plan comes the closest to what I would propose, but I would take it a step further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sanders plan includes adding a new 11% tax to payroll to help fund the medicare for all. 7.5% to be paid by the employer and 4% to be paid by the employee. This is one key place I would raise taxes. I would introduce a sliding scale.  My idea would raise the payroll tax to 15%, but add a couple new caveats. The first of which, is that the employer can choose to pay the whole 15%, but can pay no less than 7.5%. The second caveat is that I would introduce a &lt;strong&gt;CITY by CITY&lt;/strong&gt; income scale, based on where the employer’s office is and where the employees work. In this scale, there will be a floor income range. In this income range, it will penalize the employer by assigning a different percentage of the health care tax they have to pay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an illustration, for the sake of round numbers I am going to work off the current federal minimum wage and the cost of living in Nashville. The minimum wage is where the floor needs to be set, since it is the minimum that an employee can be paid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7.25 * 40 * 52 = 15,080 per year&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I cannot find good reliable statistics, lets say the cost of living in Nashville is $2000 a month. An employee making the federal minimum wage is $4,820 below the floor in Nashville. So employees making minimum wage would realize no new tax on their checks, instead the employer would pay the full 15%. Once an employees pay hits the floor, for every percent they are above the floor, a half percent will be reduced from the employers contribution and shifted to the employee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea behind this is two fold. The first is that there are huge differences in the quality of living in different parts of the country. When a 1 bedroom apartment costs $2000 in NYC and costs $600 for the same level of apartment in another city, we cannot use the same scale. The second line of thought is you do not consume the whole employee raise with new taxes, it is a gradual shift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a side note, when you age out of the workforce, the new tax for medicare for all vanishes, but also, the standard medicare and social security taxes vanish as well. This will free up more money for seniors, without the government having to take more money in and spend an overcost to disburse it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am just a regular guy, I do not have a CBO behind me to calculate the numbers, the economic impact, I am just building off of what I have seen other candidates use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shoring-up-the-other-gap&quot;&gt;Shoring up the other gap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is another gap with medicare. It does not bring in enough money to actually fund itself. For both the new tax I am proposing and the existing medicare social security tax, the limit would need to be lifted. Right now, individuals that make over $128k a year do not pay any social security on the earnings over $128k. I propose to lift these ceilings. Sure, some people will not like it, namely the people that make over $128k. Taxes are supposed to be proportional, this is not proportional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am prepared to argue all day long that the $3750 that a person makes $50,000 a year is worth more to them than the $37,500 that a person that makes $500,000 a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a good starting place, I would love to see the numbers it generates, but unfortunately I am not in a position to actually be able to generate them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/medicare-for-all/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/medicare-for-all/</guid>
        
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Banknotes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Late last year I was browsing the internet late at night and came across a site selling banknotes. I started looking through them and I was fascinated. Looking at all of the different notes around the world was pretty interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of them were pretty low tech as far as how they were designed, while others are a lot more hi-tech than the US notes I am used to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-2-24/romania.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Romanian &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like this polymer Romanian note from 1999. It has a ton of security features, including a clear panel where you can see the wood grain of my desk. Seeing the American notes from the late 90’s, well even the ones today, I realized that our money is kind of behind the times. The US dollar has pretty much looked the same all of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kind of dig these ever changing notes from different countries, but that does add a bit of cost in collecting, when a country issues a new design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hard-to-get-notes&quot;&gt;Hard to get notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you noticed the note in the top of the post, that was one that was a little harder to get. Its a North Korean Won. The embargoes we have with DPRK make it difficult to currency from there. That compounded with I don’t think people actually leave there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-2-24/rial.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Iranian Rial&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or like the Rial above featuring Ayatollah Khomeini from Iran. Since the US does not trade with Iran, they are increasingly harder to get. Not like super rare, but no where near the conversion rate either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a funny story about getting them actually. I ordered the won, the rial, some syrian dollars, and a few other banknotes one night in a drunken shopping spree. The federal government placed a hold and an investigation on my order. I actually got an email about it. It took around 3 days, but my account and that specific transaction were frozen. It was more annoying than anything, but I guess it is something to watch out for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-2-24/libya.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Libyan Dinar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is just something fascinating about all of this to me. I remember Libya from &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Back to the Future&lt;/code&gt;, now I own Libyian Dinar with Gaddafi on them before the US deposed him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me it is like owning a bit of history. So far I have around 800 or so different notes, with plans on buying more. The conversion value of them is low, but to me the art value of them is high.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/banknotes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/banknotes/</guid>
        
        
        <category>hobbies</category>
        
        <category>banknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Starting Growing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are familiar with me, you know that I work from an office in my home. I have an awesome commute, but it gets boring looking at the same walls every day. So lately I have started picking up more hobbies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The newest hobby is trying my hand at growing things. I bought some succulents at first, which I have managed to keep alive for several months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-2-20/long-pot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Long succulent pot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far they seem to be doing well. I am not an expert, but at least they are not dead yet. Trying my hand at the succulents made me want to branch out even more. I decided to start a garden this year and try growing some of my own food and spices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I searched around online and bought a ton of seeds from several different vendors, so I could start the seeds indoors, to have plants to plant when the weather warmed up. For the most part this worked pretty well. Almost all of the seeds I planted germinated and started to grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/post-2-20/plants.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Long succulent pot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is only a small fraction of what germinated, I have a feeling I went a bit overboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far what I have sprouting is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Green Zebra Tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dark Galaxy Tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Black Krim Tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pink Brandywine Tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cherokee Purple Tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Atomic Grape Tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get Stuffed Tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for peppers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aji Charapita&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brazilian Starfish&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Carolina Reapers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Apocalypse Scorpions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paprika&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Manganji&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And spices&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cilantro&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lemon Cilantro&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oregano&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Large Leaf Basil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lime Basil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know, its a bit overboard, but I cannot wait to see how things make it in the garden, that I have still yet to build. I guess the beds for the garden will be another post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/growing-things/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/growing-things/</guid>
        
        
        <category>hobbies</category>
        
        <category>gardening</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Break In</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week when I was minding my own business working on a project, a guy had different designs for me. He decided that he wanted to break into the toolbox on my truck. I guess unlucky for him all I have in my toolbox is some bags of cat food and charcoal I bought at a going out of business sale for a grocery store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can only imagine how mad my feral cats would be if he had taken the cat food, luckily enough for them he left empty handed. I did get a video him doing though, which to me is a fun watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1vm3wqpvxb8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes the situation even more ironic, or worse, is that after he left my house, he drove a little way down the street and broke into my neighbors truck as well. Because of the angle of the other camera, I have that on tape as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DmiddU7qhww&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anyone is wondering, I have an Ezviz camera system, it is the 1080p model. I thought it was a good system, but in the dark (when crime usually happens) the detail is just not there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/break-in/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/break-in/</guid>
        
        
        <category>life things</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
